Finding Aid for Episcopal Church, Diocese of Western Michigan records, 1851-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Episcopal Church, Diocese of Western Michigan records
1851-2011
Episcopal Church. Diocese of Western Michigan.
Governing body of the Episcopal church in western Michigan, established in 1874; records include bishops' files, diocesan organization and committee files, photographs, scrapbooks, diocesan historian files.
86125 Ba 2
119 linear feet
2 oversize folders
1 drawers
19 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The bulk of the record group was received in four accessions, 1972, 1990, 1994, 1998, and 2012. Periodic additions are expected. (Donor no. 5247 )
The records are open for research.
Although the Episcopal Diocese of Western Michigan was not established until 1874, the Episcopal Church first began ministering in this areas as early as the 1820s. In the first decade after the Civil War, many new parishes and mission were established, leading to the establishment of a diocese separate from the Diocese of Michigan in December of 1874.
Elected on the first ballot, Reverend George D. Gillespie was chosen as the first Bishop of the Diocese. Bishop Gillespie began his association with the Diocese of Western Michigan as rector of St. Andrew's in Ann Arbor. He was consecrated as Bishop on the Feast of St. Matthias February 24, 1875 in St. Mark's Church in Grand Rapids. The limitations of advancing age brought about the election of his future replacement, the Rt. Reverend John N. McCormick, in 1906. Bishop Gillespie suffered a stroke in February of 1907 and consequently resigned in the spring of the following year. He died on March 19, 1909.
Bishop McCormick served an eight year rectorate at St. Mark's in Grand Rapids before being elected to serve as Bishop of the Diocese. Bishop McCormick succeeded Bishop Gillespie in 1909 and served a thirty year term. On January 21, 1936 his 30th anniversary of consecration, Bishop McCormick asked the 62nd Annual Convention of the Diocese to elect a new Bishop. Bishop McCormick died three years later on November 26, 1939.
The third Bishop of the Diocese, the Rt. Reverend Lewis B. Whittemore, was born on June 17, 1885. He served as rector of Grace Church, Grand Rapids before his election in 1936. Bishop Whittemore helped found two new congregations, St. Francis in Orangeville and St. Mary's in Cadillac. During his episcopacy, the "Bishop's News Letter" was established, the Women's Auxiliary was refashioned into the Episcopal Churchwomen, and the Bishop Whittemore Foundation was developed. At the 1952 Convention, Bishop Whittemore submitted his resignation and retired on June 16, 1953. He died on December 5, 1965.
At a special convention on March 17, 1953 Rev. Dudley B. McNeil was appointed Bishop Coadjutor. Prior to his election, he served at Sault Ste. Marie. Bishop McNeil helped to start many new congregations in the Diocese, including St. Andrew's in Grand Rapids, St. John's in Fremont, St. Gregory's in Muskegon, and St. James on Beaver Island. In the summer of 1959 Bishop McNeil resigned due to ill health. The details of his subsequent life and death were not readily available in Diocesan records.
Rt. Reverend Charles E. Bennison, the fifth Bishop of the Diocese of Western Michigan, was born on July 23, 1917. He was elected Bishop Coadjutor on November 24, 1959 and consecrated as Bishop on February 24, 1960 85 years after the first Bishop was consecrated. Bishop Bennison began his career in the Diocese of Western Michigan as rector of St. Luke's in Kalamazoo, Michigan. During his episcopacy, Bishop Bennison re-established the deaneries of the diocese, began a companion relationship with the Dioceses of Kimberley and Kuruman, South Africa, formed the Commission on Ministry, Ordained and oversaw discussions on ordained women priests and human sexuality.
Perhaps the most noted accomplishment of Bishop Bennison's career was the Diocesan Center's move from Grand Rapids to Kalamazoo and the subsequent building of the Cathedral Church of Christ the King. In 1964 at the 90th Annual Convention Meeting, Kalamazoo was designated See City. One year later, the Convention voted to embark upon a two million dollar capital funds drive to build the Cathedral and Diocesan Center. Construction began in 1967 and the Cathedral was dedicated two years later.
Bishop Bennison retired in 1984 and was succeeded by Bishop Howard S. Meeks. Bishop Meeks was elected Bishop Coadjutor at the 109th Annual Convention, and was consecrated on October 6, 1984. In January 1988 Bishop Meeks resigned effective February 1st. The Standing Committee and Executive Council took charge of The Diocese and the Rt. Reverend Lyman C. Ogilby accepted the invitation to become an "Episcopal Visitor" during the interim.
At a special convention held on June 3, 1989 Rev. Edward L. Lee was selected as Bishop Coadjutor to fill the position left vacant by Bishop Meeks. He served as rector of St. John's Church, Georgetown Parish in Washington, D.C. before coming to Michigan. He was consecrated on November 26, 1989.
Robert R. Gepert was elected bishop October 19, 2001 consecrated April 27, 2002 and retired in August 2013. During his tenure, the diocese has faced significant financial challenges, and, in 2007 the Cathedral of Christ the King was sold.
Summary Contents List
Bishops George D. Gillespie, Outsize Volumes 1-5 (1994 Accession) Lewis B. Whittemore, Boxes 1-16 Charles E. Bennison, Boxes 17-42 (1990, 1994-1995 Accessions) Howard S. Meeks, Boxes 43-48 (1994-1995 Accessions) Edward L. Lee, Boxes 74-97 (2005 Accessions) Robert R. Gepert, Boxes 110-111 (2010 Accessions)
Chancellor Charles L. Dibble, Boxes 49-50 Burritt Hamilton, Box 50 Niel Weathers, Box 51
Treasurer Harry C. Angell, Boxes 51-52 Norman A. Lilly, Box 52
Diocesan Historiographer Rev. Franklin Smith, Boxes 53-54 Maurice F. Thomas, Box 55 (1990 Accession) Betty Sutton, Boxes 103-107 (2008 Accession)
Standing Committee Files, Boxes 55 and 56
Miscellaneous Files, Boxes 56-57 and oversize volume 6
Publicity Files (Elizabeth Slye), Boxes 57 and 58
Defunct Parish and Mission Church Files, Boxes 58-60; and oversize volumes 12-14 (1994 Accession)
Diocesan Committee Files, Boxes 61-63 (1990 Accession)
Diocesan Organization Files, Boxes 63-64 (1990 Accession)
Diocesan Financial Records, Boxes 65-68 (1998 Accession)
Diocesan Record Books, oversized volumes 7-11 (1994 Accession)
Visual Materials, Box 69, Box 108, oversized volume 15 and in oversize folders (UBAl) and (UBAm) (1994 and 2008 Accessions)
Sound Recordings, Box 109 (2008 accession)
Scrapbooks, Boxes 70, and oversized volumes 16-18 (1994 Accession)
Western Michigan University (WMU) Ministry Files, Box 71 (1994 Accession)
Women's Organization Files, Boxes 72-73 (1998 Accession)
Miscellaneous office and staff files, Boxes 98-102, 112-114 (2008 and 2010 Accessions)
Bulletins of church services – Cathedral Church of Christ the King, Boxes 115-117 (2010 Accession)
Church of Christ the King, Boxes 118-119, and oversized volume 19 (2012 accession)
Miscellaneous parish materials, Box 120 (2012 accession)
Miscellaneous diocesan materials, Box 120 (2012 accession)
The records of the Episcopal Diocese of Western Michigan are a rich resource of material, not only for the programs and activities of the Episcopal Church in western Michigan, but also for their documentation of the role of the church in the life of the various communities served by the diocese.
Records from the Episcopal Diocese of Western Michigan first came to the Bentley Historical Library in 1972. Since then, the diocese has made several significant additions to their records. In 1999 the record group was reprocessed with the aim of drawing together like materials. The record group now consists of twenty-two separate series. These are: Bishop's Files, Chancellor, Treasurer, Diocesan Historiographer, Standing Committee Files, Miscellaneous Files, Diocesan Record Books, Publicity Files, Defunct Parish and Mission Churches Files, Diocesan Committee Files, Diocesan Organization Files, Diocesan Financial Records, Visual Materials, Sound Recordings, Scrapbooks, Western Michigan University (WMU) Ministry Files, Women's Organizations, Miscellaneous office and staff files Bulletins of Church Services, Church of Christ the King, Miscellaneous parish materials, and Miscellaneous diocesan materials.
Subjects:
Albion (Calhoun County, Mich.); All Saints Episcopal Church (Saugatuck, Mich.); Allegan (Mich.); Baldwin (Mich.); Battle Creek (Mich.); Benton Harbor (Mich.); Big Rapids (Mich.); Cadillac (Mich.); Chapel of St. John-By-The-Lake (Onekama, Mich.); Chapel of the Good Shepherd (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Charlevoix (Mich.); Charlotte (Mich.); Christ Episcopal Church (Charlevoix, Mich.); Christ Episcopal Church (Homer, Mich.); Christ Episcopal Church (Plainfield, Mich.); Church of Christ the King (Kalamazoo, Mich.); Church of the Epiphany (South Haven, Mich.); Church of the Good Shepherd (Allegan, Mich.); Church of the Holy Trinity (Manistee, Mich.); Clare (Mich.); Coldwater (Mich.); Dowagiac (Mich.); East Jordan (Mich.); Eaton Rapids (Mich.); Elk Rapids (Mich.); Emmanuel Episcopal Church (Hastings, Mich.); Emmanuel Episcopal Church (Petoskey, Mich.); Episcopal Church. Diocese of Western Michigan.; Episcopal Church--Michigan.Michigan.; Episcopal Mission (Frankfort, Mich.); Frankfort (Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Holland, Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Ludington, Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Lyons, Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Traverse City, Mich.); Grand Haven (Mich.); Grand Ledge (Mich.); Grand Rapids (Mich.); Greenville (Mich.); Harbor Springs (Mich.); Hastings (Mich.); Holland (Mich.); Homer (Mich.); Ionia (Mich.); Kalamazoo (Mich.); Lee (Allegan County, Mich.: Township); Ludington (Mich.); Lyons (Mich.); Manistee (Mich.); Marshall (Mich.); Mendon (Mich.); Michigan--Church history.; Mission of the Redeemer (East Jordan, Mich.); Mount Pleasant (Mich.); Muskegon (Mich.); Newaygo (Mich.); Niles (Mich.); Onekama (Mich.); Orangeville (Mich.); Paw Paw (Mich.); Pentwater (Mich.); Petoskey (Mich.); Plainfield (Kent County, Mich.); Redeemer Episcopal Church (Whitehall, Mich.); Rockford (Mich.); St. Andrew's Episcopal Church (Big Rapids, Mich.); St. Ann's Episcopal Church (Clare, Mich.); St. Francis Episcopal Church (Orangeville, Mich.); Neighborhood House (Orangeville, Mich.); St. James Episcopal Church (Albion, Calhoun County, Mich.); St. James' Episcopal Church (Pentwater, Mich.); St. James Episcopal Church (Rockford, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Charlotte, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Grand Haven, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Harbor Springs, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Ionia, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Mount Pleasant, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Sturgis, Mich.); Saint Joseph (Mich.); St. Luke's Episcopal Church (Kalamazoo, Mich.); St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Coldwater, Mich.); St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Newaygo, Mich.); St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Paw Paw, Mich.); St. Mary's Episcopal Church (Cadillac, Mich.); St. Matthew's Episcopal Church (Baldwin, Mich.); St. Matthias' Episcopal Church (Eaton Rapids, Mich.); St. Michael and All Angels' Episcopal Church (Lee, Allegan County, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Dowagiac, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Elk Rapids, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Greenville, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Mendon, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Muskegon, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Saint Joseph, Mich.); St. Philip's Episcopal Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); St. Stephen's Episcopal Church (Benton Harbor, Mich.); St. Thomas Episcopal Church (Battle Creek, Mich.); Saugatuck (Mich.); South Haven (Mich.); Sturgis (Mich.); Three Rivers (Mich.); Traverse City (Mich.); Trinity Church (Niles, Mich.); Trinity Episcopal Church (Grand Ledge, Mich.); Trinity Episcopal Church (Marshall, Mich.); Trinity Episcopal Church (Three Rivers, Mich.); Whitehall (Mich.); Women--Religious life--Michigan.; Women--Michigan--Societies and clubs.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Churches--Michigan.; Clergymen.; Conway (Mich.)--Churches.; Episcopal Church--Michigan.Michigan.; Episcopal Church. Diocese of Western Michigan.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Ada.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Albion (Calhoun County); Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Allegan.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Battle Creek.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Beaver Island.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Benton Harbor.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Benzonia.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Big Rapids.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Cadillac.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Cascade.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Elk Rapids.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Fremont.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Grand Haven.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Grand Junction.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Grand Ledge.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Greenville.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Gull Lake.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Harbor Springs.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Hastings.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Holland.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Ionia.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Kalamazoo.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Kentwood.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Lakeside.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Lansing.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Ludington.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Manistee.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Montague.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Mount Pleasant.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Muskegon.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Newaygo.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Niles.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Omena.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Onekema.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Orangeville.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Pentwater.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Petoskey.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Plainwell.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Portage.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Richland.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Saint Johns.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Saint Joseph.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Saugatuck.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--South Haven.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Sparta.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Sturgis.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Three Rivers.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Traverse City.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Whitehall.; Episcopal church buildings--Michigan--Wyoming.; Starr Commonwealth for Boys.
Contributors:
Bennison, Charles E., 1917-; Gillespie, George D. (George De Normandie), 1819-1909.; Meeks, Howard S.; White, William C.; Whittemore, Lewis Bliss, 1885-
Genre/Form:
Photographs.; Diaries.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.
- Bishops' Files
  The Bishops series consists of six sub-series covering the papers of Bishops George D. Gillespie, Lewis B. Whittemore, Charles E. Bennison, Howard S. Meeks, Edward L. Lee, and Robert R. Gepert.
  - George D. Gillespie
    The George D. Gillespie subseries consists of five record volumes dating from 1875-1908 and documenting this bishop's activities within the diocese.
    - Record Books, 1875-1908; 5 volumes
      - Record Books, 1875-1908 (Volume 1)
      - Record Books, 1875-1908 (Volume 2)
        (continued)
      - Record Books, 1875-1908 (Volume 3)
      - Record Books, 1875-1908 (Volume 4)
      - Record Books, 1875-1908 (Volume 5)
  - Lewis B. Whittemore
    The Lewis B. Whittemore sub-series is further divided into Parish and Mission Correspondence which is arranged alphabetically by the name of the city where the individual Episcopal parish or mission is located; and Topical Files that include correspondence and information about diocesan activities and property.
    - Parish and Mission Correspondence
      - Albion, 1935-1953; 14 folders (Box 1)
      - Allegan, 1935-1956; 12 folders (Box 1)
      - Battle Creek, 1903-1942; 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Battle Creek, 1943-1953; 4 folders (Box 2)
      - Benton Harbor, 1936-1953; 10 folders (Box 2)
      - Big Rapids, 1918-1953; 10 folders (Box 2)
      - Cadillac, 1939-1942; 4 folders (Box 2)
      - Cadillac, 1943-1954; 5 folders (Box 3)
      - Charlevoix, 1936-1953; 5 folders (Box 3)
      - Charlotte, 1936-1953; 6 folders (Box 3)
      - Coldwater, 1929-1953; 10 folders (Box 3)
      - Dowagiac, 1927; 1936-1938; 3 folders (Box 3)
      - Dowagiac, 1939-1953; 8 folders (Box 4)
      - East Jordan, 1924 (Box 4)
      - Eaton Rapids, 1952-1953 (Box 4)
      - Elk Rapids, 1934-1953 (Box 4)
      - Frankfort (See also Manistee), 1946-1947 (Box 4)
      - Grand Haven, 1936-1954; 11 folders (Box 4)
      - Grand Ledge, 1936-1946; 5 folders (Box 4)
      - Grand Ledge, 1947-1953; 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Grand Rapids
        - Grace Church, 1937-1953; 4 folders (Box 5)
        - St. Mark's, 1924-1953; 11 folders (Box 5)
        - St. Paul's, 1925-1953; 6 folders (Box 5)
        - St. Philip's, 1932; 1936-1953; 6 folders (Box 6)
      - Greenville, 1936-1953; 6 folders (Box 6)
      - Harbor Springs, 1938-1953; 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Hastings, 1931-1953; 9 folders (Box 6)
      - Hol, 1935-1941; 4 folders (Box 6)
      - Hol, 1942-1953; 4 folders (Box 7)
      - Ionia, 1936-1953; 7 folders (Box 7)
      - Kalamazoo, 1937-1953; 16 folders (Box 7)
      - Lee Township, 1945-1948 (Box 7)
      - Lee Township, 1949-1953; 4 folders (Box 8)
      - Ludington, 1936-1953; 12 folders (Box 8)
      - Lyons, 1945-1946 (Box 8)
      - Manistee, 1935-1947; 10 folders (Box 8)
      - Manistee, 1948-1953; 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Marshall, 1936-1954; 9 folders (Box 9)
      - Mendon, 1946-1950 (Box 9)
      - Mount Pleasant, 1936-1953; 9 folders (Box 9)
      - Muskegon, 1936-1945; 7 folders (Box 9)
      - Muskegon, 1946-1953; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Newaygo, 1937-1953; 4 folders (Box 10)
      - Niles, 1936-1953; 11 folders (Box 10)
      - Onekama, 1928-1953 (Box 10)
      - Orangeville Township, 1941-1944; 5 folders (Box 10)
      - Orangeville Township, 1944-1953; 5 folders (Box 11)
      - Orangeville, 1951-1953 (Box 11)
      - Paw Paw, 1936-1953; 8 folders (Box 11)
      - Pentwater, 1937-1953; 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Petoskey, 1936-1944; 10 folders (Box 11)
      - Petoskey, 1945-1953; 6 folders (Box 12)
      - Rockford, 1932 (Box 12)
      - St. Joseph, 1936-1953; 9 folders (Box 12)
      - Saugatuck, 1917; 1932-1954; 9 folders (Box 12)
      - South Haven, 1936-1939; 5 folders (Box 12)
      - South Haven, 1940-1953; 9 folders (Box 13)
      - Sturgis, 1936-1953; 7 folders (Box 13)
      - Three Rivers, 1936-1945; 7 folders (Box 13)
      - Three Rivers, 1946-1953; 4 folders (Box 14)
      - Traverse City, 1936-1953; 11 folders (Box 14)
      - Whitehall, 1938 (Box 14)
    - Topical File
      - Akeley Hall, 1922-1943 (Box 14)
      - Anglo-Saxon Federation, 1941-1942 (Box 14)
      - Anniversary of the Diocese (Box 14)
      - Bishop's Correspondence, 1944-1949; 8 folders (Box 14)
      - Bishop's Correspondence, 1950-1951; 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Brough, Maud, 1945-1951 (Box 15)
      - Brough Community Association, 1942-1945; 6 folders (Box 15)
      - Building Fund, 1947-1950 (Box 15)
      - Fletcher Farm, 1934-1947 (Box 15)
      - Funds-Diocesan, 1945-1957; 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Gorham, F.A., 1919-1935 (Box 15)
      - McCormick, John (Bishop), 1936-1939; 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous, 1945-1950 (Box 15)
      - Seabury-Western Special Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 15)
      - Seminaries, 1946-1952; 7 folders (Box 15)
      - Tustin Trust, 1937-1938 (Box 15)
      - Candidates for the Ministry, 1944-1957 (Box 16)
  - Charles E. Bennison
    The papers of Charles E. Bennison, the third subseries in the Bishop's Files series, includes Correspondence, Topical Files, and Parish and Mission Files.
    - Correspondence File
      - 1975-1978, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Topical File, 1956-1987
      - "A", 1979-1984 (Box 17)
      - Aging, 1976-1984 (Box 17)
      - Alcoholism and Substance Abuse, 1978-1984 (Box 17)
      - Arts Committee, 1969-1975 (Box 17)
      - "B", 1979-1985 (Box 17)
      - Bicentennial, United States, 1975-1976 (Box 17)
      - Bishop Whittemore Foundation, 1969-1984; 11 folders (Box 17)
      - Bishop's Advisory Committee on Aspirants for Ministry (BACAM) (Box 17)
      - General, 1976-1984; 5 folders (Box 17)
      - Conferences, 1972-1977 (Box 17)
      - Bishop's Bulletin, 1979-1984; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Bishop's Cabinet, 1971-1983 (Box 17)
      - Bishop's United Investment of Lay Discipleship (BUILD), 1960-1971 (Box 18)
      - Black Clergy, 1981-1985 (Box 18)
      - Bonnell House, 1957-1975; 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Budget, 1978-1983 (Box 18)
      - "C", 1978-1983 (Box 18)
      - Candidates for Holy Orders, Examination, 1970 (Box 18)
      - Canons, 1956-1984; 4 folders (Box 18)
      - Cathedral Congregation
        - Bishop's Advisory Committee, 1972-1984; 2 folders (Box 18)
        - Budget, 1987 (Box 18)
      - Cathedral Corporation (Box 19)
        - General, 1966-1988; 10 folders (Box 19)
        - Record Book, 1966-1979; 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Cathedral Council
        - Minutes, 1986-1989; 3 folders (Box 19)
        - Retreat, 1987 (Box 19)
      - Cathedral Representatives, 1970-1974 (Box 19)
      - Cathedral Youth Group, 1980-1985 (Box 19)
      - Centennial Committee Fund, 1971-1973; 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Centennial Observance, 1974 (Box 19)
      - Chancellor, 1963-1970 (Box 19)
      - Chancellor, 1971-1981; 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Christian Education, 1961-1984; 3 folders (Box 20)
      - Christian Education Department, 1971-1978 (Box 20)
      - Christian Social Action
        - General, 1979-1985 (Box 20)
        - Church Proxy Resolutions, 1980-1983 (Box 20)
      - Christian Social Relations, 1960-1979; 5 folders (Box 20)
      - Christian Unity, National Workshop, 1982 (Box 20)
      - Church Notes Newsletter, 1960-1965 (Box 20)
      - Clergy Index
        - Active, 1952-1984 (Box 20)
        - Inactive, 1962-1983 (Box 20)
        - Non-parochial, 1936-1984 (Box 20)
      - Convention of the Diocese of Western Michigan, 1966-1967; 1970 (Box 20)
      - Convention of the Diocese of Western Michigan, Reports, 1976 (Box 20)
      - Correspondence, Clergy, 1965-1975; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Correspondence (out-of-diocese) (Box 21)
      - "Court for the Trial of a Bishop,", 1968 (Box 21)
      - "D", 1967-1984 (Box 21)
      - Daughters of the King, 1966-1978 (Box 21)
      - Day of Prayer Conference, 1970 (Box 21)
      - Deaconesses, 1962-1969 (Box 21)
      - Deacon's Program, 1975 (Box 21)
      - Deaf Ministry, 1961-1977 (Box 21)
      - Deaneries, 1966-1977; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - "Diaconal Ministry Reflections to Domestic Violence Victims," Thesis, 1986 (Box 21)
      - Diaconal Project, Women in the Church, 1985 (Box 21)
      - Diaconate
        - General, 1981-1986 (Box 21)
        - Permanent, 1965-1986; 4 folders (Box 21)
      - Diocesan Center School, 1964-1966 (Box 21)
      - Diocesan Convention
        - General, 1960-1968; 5 folders (Box 21)
      - Diocesan Convention (Box 22)
        - General, 1969-1978; 24 folders (Box 22)
        - General, 1979-1989; 22 folders (Box 23)
        - General, 1990; 2 folders (Box 24)